<speak version="1.0" xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2001/10/synthesis" xml:lang="en-US">
  <prosody rate="fast">
  <voice gender="male" age="30">
    1.1 Identifying Components of Motherboards
  </voice>
  <voice gender="female" age="30">
    The spine of the computer is the motherboard, otherwise known as the system board or mainboard.
    This is the printed circuit board (<say-as interpret-as="characters">PCB</say-as>), which is a conductive series of pathways laminated to a nonconductive substrate that lines the bottom of
    the computer and is often of a uniform color, such as olive, brown, or blue.
    It is the most important component in the computer because it connects all of the other components together.
    Figure <say-as interpret-as="cardinal">1.1</say-as> shows a typical PC system board, as seen from above. All other components are attached to this circuit board.
    On the system board, you will find the central processing unit (CPU), underlying circuitry, expansion slots, video components, random access memory (RAM) slots,
    and a variety of other chips. We will be discussing each of these components throughout this book.
  </voice>
  <voice gender="male" age="30">
    System Board Form Factors
  </voice>
  <voice gender="female" age="30">
    System boards are classified by their form factor (design), such as <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as>, micro <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as>,
    and <say-as interpret-as="characters">ITX</say-as>. Exercise care and vigilance when acquiring a motherboard and case separately. Some cases are less accommodating than
    others, and they might not be physically compatible with the motherboard you choose.
  </voice>
  <voice gender="male" age="30">
    Advanced Technology Extended
  </voice>
  <voice gender="female" age="30">
    Intel developed the Advanced Technology Extended (<say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as>) motherboard in the mid-1990s to improve upon the classic
    <say-as interpret-as="characters">AT</say-as>-style motherboard architecture that had ruled the <say-as interpret-as="characters">PC</say-as> world for many years.
    The <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as> motherboard has the processor and memory slots at right angles to the expansion cards.
    This arrangement puts the processor and memory in line with the fan output of the power supply, allowing the processor to run cooler.
    And because those components are not in line with the expansion cards, you can install full-length expansion cards—adapters that extend the full length of the
    inside of a standard computer case—in an <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as> motherboard machine.
    <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as> (and its derivatives) is the primary motherboard in use today. Standard <say-as interpret-as="characters">ATX</say-as>
    motherboards measure 12<sub alias="inches">&quot;</sub> × <say-as interpret-as="cardinal">9.6</say-as><sub alias="inches">&quot;</sub>
    (305<sub alias=" millimeters">mm</sub> × 244<sub alias=" millimeters">mm</sub>).
  </voice>
  </prosody>
</speak>